Tejas Khanna

Machine Learning Engineer

About Me

Tejas Khanna

Ahmedabad, India

(+91)9512767443 shirleyhouse20@gmail.com

I'm a machine learning engineer with a demonstrable ability to think critically and rise to occasions when I need to venture into unexplored fields of research. I am a team player who enjoys brainstorming ideas and someone who doesn't shy away from complexity or difficult problems. With a solid foundation in data structures and algorithms along with machine learning and data science, I strive my best to leverage the best of both software engineering and machine learning to solve challenging problems.

Skills

Programming Languages: C, C++, Java, Python, Javascript.

Machine Learning and Deep Learning Libraries: Tensorflow, Keras, Scikit-Learn

Data Manipulation and Visualization: Numpy, Pandas, Matplotlib, Seaborn

Web Scraping: BeautifulSoup

DevOps: Git, Docker, Kuberenetes

Web Development: HTML5, CSS, Php, MySQL

App Development: Ionic Framework

Project Management Tools: GitHub, Jira, Trello, Bitbucket

Experience

F(x) Data Labs / Machine Learning Engineer

Jan 2020 - PRESENT, AHMEDABAD

- ☐ Used the web scraping Python library BeautifulSoup to extract data and Scikit-Learn to help a client, a doctor, gain data science driven insights into how he can improve his rank on Practo.
- ☐ Worked on a deep learning model that would help in the task of video compression for a video conferencing tool by incorporating state of the art research done in the domain of image animation using a reference video.
- ☐ Worked on a Random Forest Model for classifying records in a warranty claims database as Fraudulent or Genuine.
- ☐ Spearheaded a few data science projects under the guidance of senior machine learning engineers and data scientists.

Uplers / Web Development Trainee

Jun 2019 - Sept 2019, AHMEDABAD

- ☐ Converted Adobe Photoshop design files to HTML5 web pages.
- ☐ Worked on the WordPress backend to add functionality to wordpress powered websites based on client's requirements.

Education

Gujarat Technological University / B.E

2015 - 2019, Ahmedabad

- Graduated with a CGPA of 8.5
- Participated in several debate contests in the annual cultural fests.
- Worked as the core app developer for the annual technical symposium in the college. Used Ionic Framework to build the app.
- Hosted a webinar on "The Basic Of Machine Learning" which was one amongst a series of webinars by the alumni of my institute which gave the alumni a platform to share knowledge that they have accrued over the years with the current students.

Projects

Deep Learning for Video Compression

Used a deep learning model to obtain encoded representations of a video stream for a video conferencing tool. This helped reduce the amount of data being transmitted back and forth as instead of sending the video stream itself, we sent encoded representations of the same which were decoded on the recipient's end. Websockets were used to host the models on each users' machine.

Fraud Detection With Unsupervised Learning

Used historical records to build an unsupervised model to help the international company 'Symphony'. Our task was to determine whether a transaction was fraudulent or not. We used data science techniques to gain insights and then used an unsupervised model to cluster the records and finally used a Random Forest classifier to classify each record as fraudulent or not.

Data Driven Decisions To Improve Ranking On Practo

Used various data science approaches to help a client improve his rank on this platform for doctors. Performed web scraping for data extraction with BeautifulSoup and used to scikit-learn for regression analysis.

Simple BlackJack in Python

Python implementation for BlackJack with one player and a dealer. This was built with strict emphasis on Object Oriented Modelling of the given problem.

Rudimentary Textual Analysis

Built a python script to plot the frequency of occurrence of letters and words in large text files. NumPy and Matplotlib were used along with Python 3.6 for this project.

Loan Defaulter Prediction

Given a dataset of 364 records, we had to train a classifier to predict the value of binary target variable 'loan_status' as either 1 or 0. I had built 4-KNN,DecisionTree,LogisticRegression and SVM.